A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Welfare Interests - General Files, Series P FA325
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Prohibition and Alcoholism
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Statement, June 6, 1932 - Letters of Opposition with No Response (A-H) (Box 41, Folder 444)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Statement, June 6, 1932 - Letters of Opposition with No Response (I-Z) (Box 41, Folder 445)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Statement, June 6, 1932 - Printed Material of Opposition (Box 41, Folder 446)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Statement, June 6, 1932 - Summary of Comment in Media (Box 41, Folder 447)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Prohibition Survey, 1933-1977 (Box 41, Folder 448)
    Governor H. Lehman asked John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to help in studying the liquor problem. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. suggested a broader study, which he undertook through Raymond B. Fosdick and Albert Scott. There is information on the progress of the study, use of the study's data by other authors, and the publishing of a second book. There is a copy of the 1933 press releases on the study.
    24.4
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Prohibition Survey - Royalties from Harper Brothers, 1934-1938 (Box 41, Folder 449)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Prohibition Survey - Expenses, 1933-1936 (Box 41, Folder 450)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed. There is a copy of Morris Victor Rosenbloom's "The Liquor Industry" which surveyed the laws and industry in each state.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Prohibition Survey - Miscellaneous Letters in Response (A-L), 1933 (Box 41, Folder 451)
    Most letters were of commendation, but there was some criticism.
    24.41
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Prohibition Survey - Miscellaneous Letters in Response (M-Z), 1933 (Box 42, Folder 452)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Council for Moderation, 1935-1937 (Box 42, Folder 453)
    E. Colby sparked this organization, which encouraged and promoted temperance. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed to organizing a banquet and gave the use of his name to the group. The Council broke up over the question of total abstinence vs. moderate drinking. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., E. Colby, E. Ford.
    24.5
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Council for Moderation - December 1934 Pledge, 1935-1936 (Box 42, Folder 454)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - National Conference of State Liquor Administrators Survey, 1937-1939 (Box 42, Folder 455)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made a $5,000 contribution toward the study of drinking habits of American youth in 1937. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.
    24.6
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Alcoholics Anonymous, Alcoholic Foundation, 1940-1960 (Box 42, Folder 456)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. was interested in AA. Members of his staff were on the board of trustees of the Alcoholic Foundation. There is information on the expansion of AA, the success of its work, and its tributes to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s assistance. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, A. L. Chapman.
    24.7
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Alcoholics Anonymous, Alcoholic Foundation - Dinner, February 1940 (Box 42, Folder 457)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. sponsored a dinner to raise funds for AA, and Nelson A. Rockefeller presided.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Alcoholics Anonymous, Alcoholic Foundation - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Family Gifts, 1938-1949 (Box 42, Folder 458)
    Contributions were made through the Riverside Church.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Alcoholics Anonymous, Alcoholic Foundation - Contributions from Various People, 1940 (Box 42, Folder 459)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - National Committee for Education on Alcoholism, 1944-1958 (Box 42, Folder 460)
    Appeals for aid were declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
    24.8
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Anti-Saloon League of Colorado, 1914-1916 (Box 42, Folder 461)
    John D. Rockefeller contributed $10,000 anonymously in 1914 and $5,000 in 1916. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - New York Anti-Saloon League, 1914-1917 (Box 42, Folder 462)
    There is a description of conditions in New York in 1919 as seen by an avid prohibitionist. The League shifted to law enforcement problems after passage of the Eighteenth Amendment. There were appeals for contributions and a "disagreement" between Raymond B. Fosdick and W. H. Anderson over the decision to cut Rockefeller funds. Here are copies of an open letter of accusation addressed to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. from W. H. Anderson. There is also information on the post-repeal situation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, Willard S. Richardson, William H. Anderson.
    24.9
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - New York Anti-Saloon League, 1918-1921 (Box 43, Folder 463)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - New York Anti-Saloon League, 1916-1920 (Box 43, Folder 464)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - New York Anti-Saloon League, 1920-1938 (Box 43, Folder 465)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - New York Anti-Saloon League - Gifts, 1923-1932 (Box 43, Folder 466)
    There are records of John D. Rockefeller's and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gifts to temperance organizations. From 1900-1918 they totaled $350,000, and from 1900-1927 they totaled $750,000.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - New York Anti-Saloon League - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Contributions, 1917-1926 (Box 43, Folder 467)
    Correspondents include William H. Anderson, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - New York Anti-Saloon League - Newspaper Articles, Enforcement Bill, 1920-1923 (Box 43, Folder 468)
    There are comments on Rockefeller contributions and Anderson's fight with Raymond B. Fosdick.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - New York Anti-Saloon League - Statements in Press about John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Contributions, 1919-1923 (Box 43, Folder 469)
    Copy of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s statement, March 7, 1919, to the "New York Herald Tribune" and attacks on John D. Rockefeller, Jr. by a fringe "wet" paper in Indiana. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - New York Anti-Saloon League - John D. Rockefeller Contributions, 1899-1904 (Box 43, Folder 470)
    Reports on the League's work and budget, John D. Rockefeller's gifts, and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gifts after 1916.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - New York Anti-Saloon League - John D. Rockefeller Contributions, 1905-1913 (Box 43, Folder 471)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - New York Anti-Saloon League - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Contributions - Allied Citizens of America, 1919 (Box 43, Folder 472)
    Allied Citizens was an organization to help enforce prohibition. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave a large gift.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Anti-Saloon League of America, 1917-1937 (Box 43, Folder 473)
    Reports on the national League's work. John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed regularly but discontinued contributions in 1926. Material on the later years reflects the friendship between H. H. Russell, the sectional organizer and president, and John D. Rockefeller. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, Howard Russell.
    24.11
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Anti-Saloon League of America - Fund for Dr. Russell, 1937-1943 (Box 43, Folder 474)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $2,500 towards debts. There are friendly letters between Dr. Russell and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Ohio Anti-Saloon League, 1897-1907 (Box 44, Folder 475)
    Reports on the progress of prohibition in Ohio and League reports. John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave annual and special contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Frederick T. Gates, Willard S. Richardson, Raymond B. Fosdick.
    24.12
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Ohio Anti-Saloon League, 1908-1929 (Box 44, Folder 476)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Research Council on Problems of Alcohol, 1937-1949 (Box 44, Folder 477)
    This was a medical study of alcoholism, unrelated to AA. There was no Rockefeller interest. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - War Prohibition, 1919 (Box 44, Folder 478)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed $5,000 for a study by the Committee on War Prohibition. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    24.14
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - War Prohibition - United Committee on War Temperance Activities, 1917-1919 (Box 44, Folder 479)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made a contribution to an organization working with camps. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - War Prohibition - Committee on War Prohibition, 1917 (Box 44, Folder 480)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Non-Partisan Women's Christian Temperance Union, 1899-1912 (Box 44, Folder 481)
    John D. Rockefeller gave an annual contribution to the Cleveland Union, based on his friendship with its leaders rather than its program. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Printed Matter on Prohibition - "The Annals," September 1932 (Box 44, Folder 482)
    September 1932 publication of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, subtitled, "Prohibition: A National Experiment."
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Printed Matter on Prohibition - Anti-Prohibition Groups, 1925-1931 (Box 44, Folder 483)
    Publications of The Moderation League and the Local Self-Government League, 1925-1931, and of the Association Against the Prohibition Amendment, 1929-1930.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Printed Matter on Prohibition - Government Publications, 1927-1932 (Box 44, Folder 484)
    Government proceedings in Quebec, New York, and the United States Senate.
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Printed Matter on Prohibition - Miscellaneous Organizations, 1927-1932 (Box 44, Folder 485)
  - Prohibition and Alcoholism - Printed Matter on Prohibition - Miscellaneous People, 1929-1933 (Box 44, Folder 486)
- Settlements
  - Settlements - Alta House, 1900-1908 (Box 45, Folder 487)
    Settlement in Cleveland's "Little Italy" was named after Alta Rockefeller. John D. Rockefeller's annual pledge to the budget was $14,000 from 1916 to 1919. In 1919 the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial Fund took over the annual gifts, reducing them as local support grew. There is information on the Fiftieth Anniversary Celebration and the end of Rockefeller assistance. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson.
    40
  - Settlements - Alta House, 1916-1953 (Box 45, Folder 488)
  - Settlements - Alta House - Harry Sims, 1922-1940 (Box 45, Folder 489)
    Sims was President of the House for several years.
  - Settlements - Alta House - G. D. Rudd, 1900-1910 (Box 45, Folder 490)
    Some gifts to the House were given through Mr. Rudd. Correspondents include G. D. Rudd, John D. Rockefeller.
  - Settlements - Alta House - Contributions, 1901-1927 (Box 45, Folder 491)
  - Settlements - Alta House - Library, 1908-1918 (Box 45, Folder 492)
    John D. Rockefeller financed the building of a branch of the public library near Alta House.
  - Settlements - Alta House - Library - Deeds to Library and House, 1930-1931 (Box 45, Folder 493)
  - Settlements - Social Halls Association in New York, 1901-1930 (Box 45, Folder 494)
    This was a stock corporation to build clubs in poorer sections of the city, which hoped eventually to be a profit-making venture. John D. Rockefeller invested $12,500 but only got $3,700 back when the organization dissolved after running a hall on the East Side for a while. Correspondents include Lillian D. Wald, Jacob Schif, Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller.
    43
  - Settlements, 1918-1956 (Box 45, Folder 495)
    Some small donations were given to various settlement houses in New York but most appeals were declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Settlements, 1942-1961 (Box 45, Folder 496)
  - Settlements - Flanner House, 1947-1954 (Box 45, Folder 497)
    Appeals were declined.
  - Settlements - Hudson Guild, 1922-1960 (Box 45, Folder 498)
    Appeals were declined until David Rockefeller gave $100 in 1960.
  - Settlements - Association for Practical House-keeping Centers, 1923-1931 (Box 45, Folder 499)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $2,700 toward establishing a model kitchen in connection with this New York public school program. Later requests were denied. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson.
    43A
  - Settlements - Bowling Green Neighborhood Association, 1919-1935 (Box 45, Folder 500)
    The Association did settlement work in Lower Manhattan. John D. Rockefeller gave $500 in 1919 and $2,500 from 1925 to 1930. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Thomas B. Appleget.
    43B
  - Settlements - East Side House Settlement, 1939-1960 (Box 45, Folder 501)
    David Rockefeller gave a gift in 1945 and Laurance S. Rockefeller contributed in 1951. Correspondents include Margaret (Peggy) McGrath Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    43E
  - Settlements - Greenwich House, 1914-1955 (Box 46, Folder 502)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller contributed. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    43G
  - Settlements - Greenwich House - Pledge, June 10, 1927, 1926-1934 (Box 46, Folder 503)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave toward the building fund for an art school and maintenance.
  - Settlements - Greenwich House - Music School, 1925-1947 (Box 46, Folder 504)
  - Settlements - Goddard-Riverside Community Center, 1944-1950 (Box 46, Folder 505)
    This was a successor to the Goddard Neighborhood Center and the Riverside Community House. Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, David Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller 3rd contributed. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, David Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    43G1
  - Settlements - Goddard-Riverside Community Center, 1951-1961 (Box 46, Folder 506)
  - Settlements - Good Neighbor Federation, 1945-1951 (Box 46, Folder 507)
    This East Side settlement house was supported by the Jewish Federation until 1947. When the neighborhood became increasingly Puerto Rican, the city took over the settlement house's support. There was no Rockefeller interest. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard.
    43G2
  - Settlements - Garment Center Community House, 1947-1950 (Box 46, Folder 508)
    All invitations to dinners were declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    43G3
  - Settlements - Grand Street Settlement, 1946-1960 (Box 46, Folder 509)
    43G4
  - Settlements - Henry Street Settlement House, 1913-1929 (Box 46, Folder 510)
    The House provided a district nursing service. John D. Rockefeller gave $25,000 in 1914 and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $2,000 in 1918 for its influenza work. Other gifts were given, and the Davison Fund made contributions in the 1930s. There are personal letters between John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Lillian Wald and information on David Rockefeller's and Laurance S. Rockefeller's special gifts. correspondents include Lillian Wald, Jerome Green, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
    43H
  - Settlements - Henry Street Settlement House, 1930-1961 (Box 46, Folder 511)
  - Settlements - Henry Street Visiting Nurse Service, 1931-1944 (Box 46, Folder 512)
    The family made contributions. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Laurance S. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Lillian Wald.
  - Settlements - Henry Street Visiting Nurse Service - Pledge, November 4, 1932, 1932-1933 (Box 46, Folder 513)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $20,000.
    See also Box 57, Folder 637.
  - Settlements - Henry Street Visiting Nurse Service - Pledge, November 25, 1933, 1933-1934 (Box 46, Folder 514)
  - Settlements - Henry Street Visiting Nurse Service - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Correspondence, 1933-1955 (Box 46, Folder 515)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd made contributions.
  - Settlements, 1918-1953 (Box 046A, Folder 0495A)
    Removed from Box 45.
  - Settlements, 1957-1961 (Box 046A, Folder 0496A)
  - Settlements - Hudson Guild, 1922-1960 (Box 046A, Folder 0498A)
  - Settlements - East Side House Settlement, 1939-1960 (Box 046A, Folder 0501A)
  - Settlements - Greenwich House, 1914-1955 (Box 046A, Folder 0502A)
    Removed from Box 46.
  - Settlements - Goddard-Riverside Community Center, 1944-1950 (Box 046A, Folder 0505A)
  - Settlements - Goddard-Riverside Community Center, 1951-1961 (Box 046A, Folder 0506A)
  - Settlements - Grand Street Settlement, 1946-1960 (Box 046A, Folder 0509A)
  - Settlements - Henry Street Settlement House, 1946-1961 (Box 046A, Folder 0511A)
  - Settlements - Henry Street Visiting Nurse Service, 1938-1941 (Box 046A, Folder 0512A)
  - Settlements - Henry Street Visiting Nurse Service - Abby Rockefeller Mauzé Contributions, 1937-1959 (Box 47, Folder 516)
  - Settlements - Visiting Nurse Service of New York, 1946-1961 (Box 47, Folder 517)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Martha Baird Rockefeller made contributions, and the Rockefeller Brothers Fund made annual contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Martha Baird Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
  - Settlements - Visiting Nurse Service of New York - Contributions, 1942-1948 (Box 47, Folder 518)
  - Settlements - Visiting Nurse Service of New York - Contributions, 1949-1961 (Box 47, Folder 518A)
  - Settlements - Visiting Nurse Service of New York - Contributions, 1949-1961 (Box 47, Folder 518B)
  - Settlements - Hull House Association, 1928-1960 (Box 47, Folder 519)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made a contribution toward the Jane Addams memorial fund but declined other appeals. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.
    43H1
  - Settlements - James Weldon Johnson Community Center, Inc., 1950-1961 (Box 47, Folder 520)
    Small contributions were made by Mary French Rockefeller and Margaret (Peggy) McGrath Rockefeller. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Mary French Rockefeller, Margaret (Peggy) McGrath Rockefeller.
    43J1
  - Settlements - James Weldon Johnson Community Center, Inc., 1954-1957 (Box 47, Folder 0520A)
  - Settlements - Judson Health Center, 1924-1956 (Box 47, Folder 521)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. made contributions but most appeals were declined. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
    43J5
  - Settlements - Lenox Hill Settlement, 1915-1960 (Box 47, Folder 522)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave a gift of $50,000 in 1927. Mary French Rockefeller served on the board. Contributions were made by other family members. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    43L
  - Settlements - Lenox Hill Settlement, 1915-1960 (Box 47, Folder 0522A)
  - Settlements - Lenox Hill Settlement - Contributions, 1926-1959 (Box 47, Folder 523)
  - Settlements - Lenox Hill Settlement - Contributions, 1926-1959 (Box 47, Folder 0523A)
  - Settlements - Lenox Hill Settlement - Contributions, 1960-1961 (Box 47, Folder 524)
  - Settlements - Lenox Hill Settlement - Contributions, 1960-1961 (Box 47, Folder 0524A)
  - Settlements - Labor Temple, 1933-1959 (Box 47, Folder 525)
    A few small gifts were given by Nelson A. Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller and Mary French Rockefeller. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Mary French Rockefeller.
    43L1
  - Settlements - Music School Settlement, 1911-1934 (Box 47, Folder 526)
    The School offered music lessons at small fees to poor children and sought to do special work through the love of music. Abby Aldrich Rockefeller made a contribution and John D. Rockefeller gave in 1915. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $1,000 annually from 1924 to 1932 and gave $500 in 1933 as his last gift. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Willard S. Richardson, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard.
    43M
  - Settlements - Manhattanville Neighborhood Center, 1944-1949 (Box 47, Folder 527)
    This was one of the Riverside Church's "benevolence" activities and included an interfaith program. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., and John D. Rockefeller 3rd made contributions. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Harry Emerson Fosdick.
    43M1
  - Settlements - Manhattanville Neighborhood Center, 1946-1949 (Box 48, Folder 528)
    This was one of the Riverside Church's "benevolence" activities and included an interfaith program. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd and David Rockefeller made contributions. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Harry Emerson Fosdick.
  - Settlements - Manhattanville Neighborhood Center, 1950-1954 (Box 48, Folder 529)
    DR material removed to Folder 529A.
  - Settlements - Manhattanville Neighborhood Center, 1950-1954 (Box 48, Folder 0529A)
  - Settlements - Manhattanville Neighborhood Center - Pledge, February 1947, 1946-1948 (Box 48, Folder 530)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave over $100,000 toward the purchase of a house.
  - Settlements - Manhattanville Community Center, Inc., 1954-1960 (Box 48, Folder 531)
    This organization was formed through the 1954 merger of the Manhattanville Day Nursery and the Manhattanville Neighborhood Center, both in Morningside Heights. The Rockefeller Brothers Fund gave grants and David Rockefeller gave annual gifts until 1958. He also attended benefit events. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Everett Case, Harry Emerson Fosdick.
  - Settlements - Morningside Community Center, 1946-1961 (Box 48, Folder 532)
    The family made contributions to the Center and its camp in New Hampshire. James Robinson had ideas about fighting communism all over the world and plans for a "peace corps." Correspondents include Everett Case, Harry Emerson Fosdick.
    43M2
  - Settlements - Morningside Community Center, 1946-1961 (Box 48, Folder 532A)
  - Settlements - Manhattanville Day Nursery, 1940-1954 (Box 48, Folder 533)
    The Nursery merged with the Manhattanville Neighborhood Center into the Manhattan Community Centers, Inc. David Rockefeller made contributions. Correspondents include David Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
    43M3
  - Settlements - Neighborhood Music School, 1921-1937 (Box 48, Folder 534)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave a total of $5,500 in 1924 and 1927. Later appeals were declined. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Thomas B. Appleget.
    43N1
  - Settlements - Prescott House, 1946-1961 (Box 48, Folder 535)
    Appeals were declined until 1961 when John D. Rockefeller 3rd gave a non-recurring gift. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    43P
  - Settlements - Riverside Community House, 1937-1959 (Box 48, Folder 536)